rodalesorganiclife.com 2016-03-29

# Your Privacy Policy | Rodale Inc

## About Us

June 26, 2015

Protecting Your Privacy and Servicing Your Needs

Rodale and its subsidiaries, (together "Rodale") the world's leading healthy lifestyle company, publishes some of the best-known health and wellness lifestyle magazines, including _Prevention_ , _Men's Health_ , _Women's Health_ , _Runner's World_ , _Running Times_ , _Bicycling_ , and _Rodale's Organic Life_ , and is one of the largest independent book publishers in the United States. Rodale brings you the ideas, insights, and information that inspire and enable people to improve their lives and the world around them. 

---|---|---  
  
This privacy policy applies to all information gathering activities of Rodale, on and offline. The policy describes how we handle information provided to us or collected on Internet sites where this privacy policy is posted. It also explains how we handle information provided to us or collected on applications we make available on or through third-party sites or platforms, if it is disclosed to you in connection with your use, purchase or download of the application. We may make changes to this policy. Please check back frequently for updates. Unless otherwise noted, any changes to this policy will take effect immediately upon being posted. Your continued use of Rodale sites, applications, products and services after the effective date of the changes constitutes your consent. 

TABLE OF CONTENTS

  1. Children Under 13
  2. Information Collection
  3. How We Use Your Information
  4. Consent
  5. Your California Privacy Rights
  6. Updating Your Information
  7. Opting-out of Email
  8. Transfers for Legal Purposes
  9. Mobile Devices
  10. Cookies and Web Beacons
  11. Do Not Track/Third-Party Advertising
  12. Links
  13. Policy Changes
  14. Data Security
  15. Contact Us

**Children Under 13**  
Rodale sites are not directed to children under 13 years of age. We care about the safety of children. We won't knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide us any personal identifying information. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as, their names, e-mail addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet to us or to anyone else. We encourage you to become involved in your children's online experience and to share your interest in our sites with your young ones.

**Information Collection**  
Personally identifying information (“PII”) is information about you as an identifiable individual. Rodale collects PII from you offline when you communicate with us by mail, fax, telephone or in person. We collect personal information with you online when you visit our website(s), through e-mail, through social media, and through the use of our mobile applications. We also collect PII during transactions, sponsored events and contests/sweepstakes. PII includes your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone and cell phone numbers, wireless service provider, and all other information that identifies you or that is subject to personal information protection legislation.

We collect information about your interaction with Rodale sites, applications and services. For example, we use website analytics tools on our site to retrieve information from your browser, including the site you came from, the search engine(s) and the keywords you used to find our site, the pages you view within our site, your browser add-ons, and your browser's width and height. We also use technologies, such as cookies and web beacons (described below), to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on our sites and services. Additionally, we collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring website addresses.

When you receive newsletters or promotional e-mail from Rodale, we use web beacons (described below), customized links or similar technologies to determine whether the e-mail has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you more focused e-mail communications or other information.

In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with Rodale, information collected through one Rodale site, application or service may be combined with information obtained through other Rodale sites, applications or services. We may also supplement the information we collect with information obtained from other companies.

**How We Use Your Information**  
We use your PII to provide you with the products (including print and online versions of our products), services and information that you have requested from us and to respond to your inquiries or applications. The information we collect allows us to customize the content and/or layout of our sites and applications for you and each other visitor. We also use your PII to notify you about updates to our websites and applications, contact you with special offers of interest, surveys and contests, and to customize your experience.

In addition, Rodale makes certain PII and other information available to trusted third parties that work with us to provide products and services to our customers, that help us with marketing campaigns, or that intend to market products and services to you directly. These companies are obligated to protect the information they receive.

We retain your PII for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it, to satisfy our legal obligations and to protect our legitimate interests. We may also aggregate your information with other people’s information or de-identify your information. We use this information in order to understand trends and to evaluate the effectiveness of our business. We may retain aggregated and de-identified information indefinitely. 

**Consent**  
By using Rodale sites, applications, products and services, you consent to our collection of PII. When you register for an account, purchase a product or service, enter a contest or promotion, communicate with us, or use interactive portions of our sites and applications, you consent to our collection of the PII in accordance with this policy that you disclose or make available to us during those activities. In some cases, we may also ask you to confirm your knowledge of the terms of this policy; however, we are not obligated to do so. 

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
As described above, from time to time, we make your PII available to third parties. If you do not want us to share your PII with other companies or organizations, you may opt-out of this information sharing by doing any one of the following: 1) accessing the form at <http://www.rodale.com/cs/customer_contact_form.php>; 2) calling us at 866-387-0509; or writing to us at Privacy Request, Rodale Inc., 400 South Tenth Street, Emmaus, PA 18098. This notice is designed to comply with California's "Shine the Light" law, but the opt-out option is available to all of our users.

**Updating Your Account and Contact Information**  
Upon request, we will update your personal account information (e.g., customer number), access your account status (outstanding balance), and update your contact information (i.e., name, address, phone number). For more information or to update an account, please visit <http://www.rodaleinc.com/customer-service>. If you prefer, you may write to us at Privacy Request, Rodale Inc., 400 South Tenth Street, Emmaus, PA 18098.

**What if I don't want commercial/promotional e-mail from Rodale?**  
If you do not want to receive commercial/promotional e-mail or online newsletters that you have subscribed to, please let us know by updating your email preferences at <http://e-rodalepartner.com/preference/welcome.jsp>, by utilizing the unsubscribe option available on commercial e-mail communications, by calling us at 866-387-0509, or by writing to us at Privacy Request, Rodale Inc., 400 South Tenth Street, Emmaus, PA 18098.

**Transfers of Information for Legal Purposes**  
Rodale may need to disclose certain information to comply with a legal requirement, such as a law, regulation, court order, subpoena, or search warrant, in the course of a legal proceeding. Rodale may also disclose information to assert or defend its legal rights or in response to a law enforcement agency request. If there is a change of control in Rodale's business (whether by merger, sale, or otherwise) or a sale or transfer of its assets, your information could be sold or transferred as part of that transaction and your PII and other information potentially used by the Purchaser or other recipient of said information.

You acknowledge that Rodale is located in the United States of America ("U.S.") and will process and store your information in the U.S., and that as a result, U.S. governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through the laws of the U.S. In addition, Rodale may use service providers which are be located outside of the U.S. or which may process or store information on behalf of Rodale outside of the U.S. If transferred to those service providers, your PII will also be subject to the laws of those other jurisdictions.

**Mobile Devices/Third Party Fees**  
From time to time, Rodale makes mobile device application and mobile marketing campaigns available to you and may allow you to register for services that involve messages and/or e-mails being sent to your mobile device. You are responsible for obtaining access to the mobile device services and that access may involve third-party fees, including mobile carrier, text messaging, or airtime charges. You are solely responsible for those fees, including any and all fees associated with the use of the applications, delivery of the messages, e-mails or other materials to your mobile device. Please consult your mobile service provider's pricing plan prior to purchasing or downloading any application or registering for any such service to determine the charges for sending and receiving text messages from/to your mobile device. You will be given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving text messages or emails to your mobile device at the time you register and with each message or email you receive.

Mobile marketing campaigns may involve your sending an e-mail from your mobile device to Rodale or a third-party campaign operator. An e-mail or other response will then be sent to your mobile device. Opting to participate in a campaign is 100% your choice. When you engage in these mobile marketing campaigns, Rodale and the third-party campaign operator may collect your cell phone number, the name of your wireless service provider, images that you send using your cell phone as part of the campaign, and other relevant information.

**What are "Cookies" and "Web Beacons" and what do they do for me?**  
In order to provide better service when you return to our site, Rodale may use Cookies and Web Beacons to store your preferences and information about such things as items added to your shopping cart, purchases you have made with us, what pages you visit, and past activity at a site. Rodale may also employ Web Beacons from third parties in order to help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns or other operations of our sites.

"Cookies" are tiny pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are also used to ensure that you are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads and to customize webpage content based on your browser type (Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, or Microsoft Explorer, for example). Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies.

Web Beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs or clear gifs - are used to assist in delivering cookies on our sites and allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. We include Web Beacons in promotional e-mail messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

If you want to disable cookies, there is a simple procedure in most Internet browsers that allows you to turn off cookies. You can also use plug-ins for your browser to see alerts for Web Beacons or to block Web Beacons when using certain browsers. You can also prevent some Web Beacons from loading by not downloading images in email messages. Please remember, however, that cookies may be required to allow you to use certain features of our sites.

**Do Not Track/Third Party Advertising**  
We use third-party advertising, data analytics and online targeting companies to serve ads when you visit our sites or use our applications. We may also provide certain PII and other information to these third-parties to allow them to more effectively target advertising to you. These companies are obligated to protect your information, but you may opt-out of this sharing through the process described here. 

When advertisements are displayed to you on our sites and applications, one or more persistent cookies will be placed on your computer or device by us or a third party. Some of these third parties may use information (including PII) about your visits to this site and other websites and usage of applications in order to provide data and targeting recommendations based on which you may receive advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. To learn more about this practice and the third-party companies we may currently be using, click [here](http://www.rodaleinc.com/third-party-advertising). To opt out of this practice and active Do Not Track, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). 

**Links**  
Rodale sites contain links to other sites with information gathering practices different from our own. Visitors should consult privacy policies for all other sites, as Rodale has no control over information submitted to or collected by such third parties.

Rodale sites sometimes offer contests, sweepstakes, or promotions sponsored or co-sponsored by third parties. These third parties may obtain PII that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. Rodale has no control over the third-party sponsor's use of this information. The Rodale site will notify you at the time of requesting PII if third-party sponsors will be provided with such information.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**  
Rodale may need to change this privacy policy from time to time in order to address new issues, evolving technologies, changes on our sites, or business practices. Rodale will post those changes so you will always know what information we gather and how we might use that information. Please refer back to this policy regularly.

**What about data security?**  
Rodale uses industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving data such as your address or credit card information exchanged with our site. You can check whether your connection is using encryption technologies by using the functions in your browser, such as whether our page is showing has having been delivered by “https”. We have also implemented other technical, physical and administrative security measures that protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you. Please note, however, that the security of your data is a shared responsibility. Our security precautions will not be effective if you access Rodale sites over an insecure WIFI connection or with a browser that has been compromised, do not clear your computer’s cache or that of a public computer, or if you share or choose an easy to guess password. 

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy statement or if you feel that this site has not followed its stated information policy, feel free to contact us. You may also contact us to request access to or request corrections to your PII. Our postal address is 400 South 10th Street, Emmaus, PA 18098, and our privacy team can be reached via e-mail at [privacy@rodale.com](mailto:privacy@rodale.com) or you may use the form located at <http://www.rodale.com/cs/index.html>. You can reach customer service by telephone at 866-387-0509. Please note that we may not release or modify your PII to you unless you are able to provide satisfactory confirmation of identity.

Additionally, you may contact your state or local consumer protection office, [The Direct Marketing Association's Committee on Ethical Business Practices](http://www.the-dma.org/index.php), the [Better Business Bureau](http://www.bbb.org/), or The Federal Trade Commission by phone at (202) FTC-HELP (202/382-4357) and online at [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/).

Rodale complies with all the stringent standards of ethical conduct set forth by the Direct Marketing Association.
